<Document>
# Hyperion Server Rules

## Foreword

Hyperion is an [bold]18+[/bold] server. We give players broad freedom to craft their own
experiences, and in return we expect you to [bold]stay in character, play in good faith, and
contribute to the experience of the people around you[/bold].

All rules below apply at all times: in-round, between rounds, and across our community spaces.

[color=red][italic]These rules are expected to be read in full. Admin decisions are final and
enforced to the spirit of the rules.[/italic][/color]

# Core Rules

## 0. You must be 18 or older.
Hyperion is an [bold]18+[/bold] server. Your real-life age must be 18 or above to play, and you
must conduct yourself accordingly. Knowingly concealing that a player is under 18 is itself a
bannable offense.

## 1. Use common sense.
Rules cannot cover every situation. Act in good faith, don't hunt for loopholes, and don't be the
reason a new rule has to be written.

## 2. Respect others.
No harassment, bigotry, hate speech, slurs, or real-world discrimination. Out-of-character
conflict is never acceptable.

## 3. No cheating or exploits.
No third-party tools, multiboxing, or game/engine exploits. Report exploits through Admin Help
instead of abusing them.

## 4. No alternate accounts.
One account per player. Evading a ban with an alt extends the ban.

## 5. Communicate in English.
Server communication (chat, Admin Help, comms) must be in English so staff can moderate it.

## 6. Use Admin Help (ahelp) properly.
Admin Help is for rule issues and questions, not abuse. Disconnecting from or evading an ahelp
results in an [color=red]appeal-only ban[/color].

## 7. Do not threaten to report players.
Raise issues through Admin Help. Don't use "I'll ahelp you" as an in-game threat or as leverage.

# Roleplay Rules

## 1. Stay in character.
Don't break character in in-character channels. Keep out-of-character talk in OOC.

## 2. Use in-character chat appropriately.
No OOC chatter, spam, or meta-talk in in-character channels.

## 3. Character names.
Use believable names. Don't name yourself after well-known real or fictional people.

## 4. Erotic roleplay is prohibited.
Despite being an 18+ server, [bold]Hyperion does not permit erotic roleplay (ERP) or sexual
content[/bold] of any kind. The 18+ gate is an administrative maturity bar, not an invitation for
NSFW content.

## 5. Do not metagame.
Don't act on information your character could not know (Discord, OOC, deadchat, streams, etc.).

# Conflict Rules

## 1. No random deathmatch (RDM).
Don't attack others without sufficient in-character reason and escalation.

## 2. New life rule.
Once you die and return, you don't retain grudges or knowledge to seek revenge for your death.

## 3. Fair play in conflict.
Escalate proportionally and give targets a reasonable chance.

# Setting-Specific Rules

[color=yellow][italic]Hyperion's setting is still being defined. Rules tied to factions, territory,
ship ownership, and safe zones will live here once the setting is established. Until then, the
Core, Roleplay, and Conflict rules above govern.[/italic][/color]

# Admin Decisions
- [color=yellow][bold]All admin decisions are final.[/bold][/color]
- Rules are enforced to the [color=yellow]spirit of the rules[/color] and subject to admin interpretation.
- Admins may set aside rules when they judge it in the best interest of the round, server, or community.
- Admins are accountable for their actions; abuse of admin powers is handled by staff.

# General Information
- Admins are not obligated to compensate player losses (deaths, deeds, money, respawns); any remedy is at staff discretion.
- For questions or to report an issue, use Admin Help (Escape &gt; Admin Help).

</Document>
